Jose Gomez

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Mobile: 832.613.3881

Email: gomez.jose853@gmail.com Web: josegomez832.github.io

LANGUAGES

- HTML/5
- CSS/3
 MySQL
- JavaScript
- Meteor

• PHP

¡Query

SKILLS

- · Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Sublime Text 2
- Sketch
- · SEO
- UI/UX
- Grunt
- Bootstrap
- Responsive Design
- · SASS
- WordPress
- Git
- REST

Awards

- 2014 Honory Mention for The Shops at Houston Center
- 2016 Latern Award for Raizner Law Landing Page

PROFILE

I am a creative web developer and designer with over 5 years of agency experience. I provide rapid, robust and client-acclaimed front-end development optimizing user experience, search engine ranking, usability and accessibility. Able to complete projects efficiently and satisfy clients with attractive, user-friendly websites.

EXPERIENCE

Forthea Interactive Marketing

Web Developer

April 2016 - Present

- Develop WordPress sites for clients such as Andrews Myers, Fine Watch Bank, Almost Home Properties, The Buckley Law Group, and Chipman Relocations
- Work with SEO and PPC team to design and develop strategic landing pages to ensure conversion rates
- Create website launch list and install SSL Certificates for all client sites going to production
- Meet with clients to gather requirements for site design and help Project Manager create timelines.
- Develop custom WordPress plugins to extend core functionality and extend functionality for theme with the hook and filter APIs
- Work with APIs such as Gemfind to import Woocommerce product feed as well as APIs like Instagram and Facebook

MMI Agency

Web Designer / Developer

May 2012 - April 2016

- Designed and developed custom WordPress themes that consisted of landing pages, blogs, ecommerce, business and multilingual websites
- · Created strategic landing pages that are optimized for conversions
- Responsible for developing Intranet portal for employees to post updates, add calendar invites and search other employees
- Designed and developed innovative marketing email campaigns with 25% clickthrough rate
- Created training manuals in PDF format on WordPress for clients such as Shell Houston Open, Air Liquide Health Care, American International Group and The Shops at Houston Center
- Produced sketches, wireframes and clickable prototypes for testing and illustration purposes

Elemental Media Group

Intern Web Developer / Designer

October 2011 - December 2011

- Developed custom XHTML/CSS website
- Implemented WordPress on existing static site
- Created social media graphics

EDUCATION

The Art Institute of Houston

2009 - 2012